After a lifetime of going from girl to girl, the ultimate
bachelor is about to encounter something new.
Something's Gotta Give is a drama, comedy,
romance film directed by Nancy Meyers.
When perpetually single, aging music industry exec Harry Sanborn, and his latest trophy girlfriend, Marin, arrive at her mother's
beach house in the Hamptons, they find that her mother, playwright Erica Barry, also plans to stay for the weekend.
Erica is scandalized by the relationship and Harry's sexist ways.
But when Harry has a heart attack while there, and the doctor prescribes
bedrest, his only option is to stay at the Barry home.
Left in the care of Erica and his doctor, a love triangle starts to take shape.
Harry Sanborn, played by Jack Nicholson.
Erica Barry, played by Diane Keaton.
Julian Mercer, played by Keanu Reeves.
Zoe, played by Frances McDormand.
Marin, played by Amanda Peet.
Leo, played by Jon Favreau.
Something's Gotta Give is a 2003 American romantic comedy drama
film written, produced, and directed by Nancy Meyers.
It stars Jack Nicholson and Diane Keaton as professionals who find love for
each other in later life, despite being complete opposites.
Keanu Reeves and Amanda Peet co-star, with Frances McDormand
and Jon Favreau playing key supporting roles.
Something's Gotta Give was released on December 12, 2003 by Sony Pictures
Releasing in the United States and Canada and by Warner Bros.
Pictures in international markets.
The film received positive reviews from critics, with praise
directed towards Keaton and Nicholson's performances.
The film emerged as a major commercial success at the box-office, grossing $266
million worldwide against a production budget of $80 million.
For her performance, Keaton received nominations for the Academy Award for Best Actress, the Critics' Choice Movie Award for
Best Actress and the Screen Actors Guild Award for Outstanding Performance by a Female Actor in a Leading Role.
At the 61st Golden Globe Awards, Keaton won Best Actress in a Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy, while
Nicholson received a nomination for Best Actor in a Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy.
The film explores themes of new york city, paris, france,
heart attack, age difference, womanizer.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.